lycatv.tv 2019-04-14

# Privacy Policy - Lyca TV

Select country code:

* * *

If you knew your credentials, click Log in

LycaTV respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy policy will inform you:

  * about how we use your personal data through your use of this website and our app, including any data you may provide us when you purchase a product or service from us or sign up to our communications.
  * about your privacy rights and
  * how the law protects you.

This privacy policy is provided in a layered format so you can choose the specific areas in which you are particularly interested.

Alternatively, you can find a summary  **here**.

We are Lyca Media Ltd, operating under the trading name of ‘LycaTV’. We are an ethnic entertainment provider and we provide a variety of online TV services to our customers.

We are a company incorporated under the Laws of England and Wales with registration number 08503593 and we are based in the UK at Wallbrook Building, 195 Marsh Wall, London, E14 9SG.

Lyca Media Ltd is a data controller and is responsible for your personal data (collectively referred to as “we”, “us” or “our” in this privacy policy).

Personal Data is any information about you from which you can be identified. It does not include data where your identity has been removed (it’s called anonymous data).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we have grouped together as follows:

  * **Identity Data  **includes your title, first name, last name.
  * **Contact Data  **includes your email address, mobile and landline contact number, full address.
  * **Billing Data** includes your details about payments about the products and services you have purchased from us, i.e., your transaction history.
  * **Technical Data** includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, time zone setting and location, including your devices.
  * **Profile Data** includes your username and password, purchases made by you, your interests, and preferences.
  * **Usage Data** includes information about how you use our website, products and services.
  * **Marketing and Communications Data** includes your preferences in receiving marketing from Lyca Media Ltd concerning its products and services.
  * **Customer Care Data** includes your feedback to us, survey responses and voice mail recordings when you contact us.
  * **Referral Data** includes the name, country, contact number and email address of the person you are referring.

Where you fail to update your personal data, we may not be able to provide you with the products or services. We may also have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.

We use different methods to collect data from you through:

**Direct interactions.** You may give us your personal data by filling in forms on our website or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise.

Your personal data is collected when you do the following:

  * Create an account and register with us
  * Order our products and services
  * Subscribe to our services or communications
  * Request marketing to be sent to you
  * Enter a competition, promotion or survey
  * Give us some feedback.
  * Download our app.

**Other sources of data:**

If you log-in using your social network credentials to connect to our platforms and online services e.g. Facebook, Twitter, and/or YouTube, your user details may be shared with us. For example, your name, email address, date of birth, location and any other information you choose to share with us.

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to, most commonly, in the following circumstances:

  * Where we need to perform the terms and conditions we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
  * To comply with a legal or regulatory obligation, where applicable. 

We have set out below,  a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are, where appropriate.

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful basis depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data.

Purpose | Type of data | Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest  
---|---|---  
To register you as a new customer | 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

| 

Performance of terms and conditions with you  
  
To supply products and services to you including:

Managing payments

Collecting money owed to us

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Billing

| 

(a) Performance of terms and conditions with you

(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to recover sums owed to us)  
  
To manage our relationship with you and administer your account which will include:

Notifying you about changes to our terms and conditions or privacy policy

Asking you to leave a review or take a survey

Manage any concerns that you raise to our customer care department

Quality assurance and monitoring purposes

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Profile

(d) Marketing and Communications

(e) Customer Care

(f) Usage

| 

(a) Performance of terms and conditions with you

(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation

(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services to serve them better)  
  
To enable you to participate in a competition or complete a survey (non-promotional)

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Profile

(d) Usage

(e) Marketing and Communications

| 

(a) Performance of terms and conditions with you

(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services to serve them better)  
  
To market products and services to you and the person you refer to us

To complete a survey (promotional)

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Marketing and Communications

(d) Profile

(e) Referral Data

| 

(a) Legitimate interest to process marketing data (to grow our business) and consent for sending electronic marketing communications for _new customers  _or reliance on _existing customer relationship_ to send electronic marketing communications  
  
To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences

| 

(a) Technical

(b) Usage

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant for clients, to inform our marketing strategy so that we serve our customers with better products and services)  
  
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you

| 

(a) Identity

(b) Contact

(c) Technical

(d) Usage

(e) Profile

| 

Necessary for our legitimate interests (to inform our marketing strategy so that we serve our customers with better products and services)  
  
**Marketing**

You will receive marketing communications from us either if you have consented to receive them or you have purchased products or services from Lyca Media Ltd, and in each case, you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.

You can ask us to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by

  * Following the opt-out links on any marketing message sent to you or
  * Contacting our Customer Services Department by filling our contact form https://www.lycatv.tv/contact.

You can also contact us to let us know whether you’re happy to hear from us by text, or telephone.

Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data provided to us as a result of a product/service purchase or other purposes.

We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the following purposes:

  * Other Lyca affiliated entities which provide ancillary services such as call centre support for the fulfilment of your orders and clarification any of your queries as well as IT technical support services.
  * External third parties who provide data centre services.

If a change happens to our business where we may choose to sell, transfer or merge parts of our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as set out in this privacy policy.

Where applicable, we require all external third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.

Some of our service providers are based outside the European Economic Area (EEA) so the processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the EEA.

Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we rely on the following lawful ground for processing:

**Category of Recipient**

| 

**Location of Recipient**

| 

**lawful ground for processing**  
  
---|---|---  
  
(1) Technical services provider

| 

Sri Lanka

| 

Consent  
  
(2) Affiliated Lyca entities for call centre support

| 

India, Manila, Sri Lanka

| 

Consent  
  
For the above countries, there are no appropriate safeguards in place. The EU recognises that these countries do not provide the same level of data protection as provided in the EU. As such, we take steps to ensure your privacy rights are at least as compliant with the requirements of EU law, including by requiring appropriate security measures from such third parties, set out in a contract between us, to protect your personal data.

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those staff members or other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a strict duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable supervisory authority of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for and to meet any legal requirements, where applicable.

When deciding what to retain, we take into account what information we need to best provide you with products, and services, manage your relationship with us, meet any statutory obligations, where applicable and meet our customers’ expectations.

In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case, we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

_Under certain circumstances_ , you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data which are as follows:

  * _Access to your personal data_ \- This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

  * _Correction of your personal data_ \- This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.

  * _Erasure of your personal data_ \- This enables you to ask us to delete personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law.

Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.

  * _Object to processing of your personal data_ – This right can be exercised where we are relying on a legitimate interest and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.

  * _Restriction of processing your personal data_ \- This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the data’s accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c) where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.

  * _Transfer of your personal data_ -This enables you to ask us to transfer your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format.

Note, however, that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please send your request to [mydata@lycagroup.com](mailto:mydata@lycagroup.com).

**No fee usually required**

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

**What we may need from you**

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

**Time limit to respond**

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

If you have any questions or would like to know more about LycaTV please do not hesitate to get in touch with us. LycaTV has a multilingual team that operates from 8am to 8pm, 7 Days a week.

You may contact our Customer Services Department by filling our contact form https://www.lycatv.tv/contact.

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the relevant data protection supervisory authority.

We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns first before you approach the supervisory authority, so please do contact us in the first instance.

For compliance questions in relation to this policy, please email us at [DPO@lycagroup.com](mailto:DPO@lycagroup.com).

**Changes to the policy**

This privacy policy applies from 25 May 2018 until such time it is updated again. Historic versions are archived here.

Watch your favourite TV shows, movies, music and more, on a wide range of devices – with just a single subscription!
